Women's Press Club of New York State; Records apap094
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records1984-1989
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Women's Press Club Of New York State Inc.
apap094
0.17 cubic ft. processed to date
The Women's Press Club of New York State, INC. Records consist of a collection of publicity materials for the organization dated from 1984 through 1989.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of one folder, which is marked.
Acquisition Information
The Women's Press Club of New York State, INC. donated all of the materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in September 2002.
Organizational Sketch
The Women's Press Club of New York State, Inc. was organized in 1966 by a group of women journalists to "foster high standards among its members through career development and recognition, to promote camaraderie among members and to conduct philanthropic and educational activities." All information is taken from the Women's Press Club of New York State, Inc. brochures. The Club now includes in its membership professional communicators in the print and electronic media, public relations, and other related fields. The organization's calendar of events includes regular meetings and professional development seminars. The Club awards scholarships to students majoring in communications fields and coordinates internship opportunities for practical experience. The Club also awards the WIN (Woman in the News) Award to an outstanding woman featured in local media as well as the Legislator of the Year and Media Person of the Year.
Scope and Contents
The Women's Press Club of New York State, Inc. records include sporadic administrative and publicity materials from 1984 through 1989. The collection includes some administrative materials such as meeting minutes, financial reports, and membership directories. The press releases, news clippings and the program folder document seminars and events hosted by the Club. The newsletters produced for members provide the most information about the organization and how it functions.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Women--New York (State)--Albany--Societies and clubs; Women in nonprofit organizations--New York (State)--Albany; Application Forms; Brochures; Directories; Financial Records; Minutes; Newsletters; Press Releases; Learning and Scholarship Concepts; The Women's Press Club of New York State, INC.; New York State Federation of Women’s Clubs
- Applications, 1987-1989 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 1)
- Brochures, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 2)
- Directory, 1986-1988 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 3)
- Financial Reports, 1985; 1988-1989 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1985; 1987-1988 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 5)
- News Clippings, 1984-1985; 1989 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 6)
- Newsletter, 1984-1985; 1987-1989 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 7)
- Programs, 1985-1989 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 8)
- Press Releases, 1984-1985; 1987 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 9)
- Reception for Legislators, 1985-1986; 1988 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 10)
- Scholarship, 1985; 1988 (Box 1 (Women's Press Club of New York State Inc. Records), Folder 11)